Phone: (+64) 22 0780868

Email: daniel@thoughtfulhq.com

Web: <a href="https://www.danielballoch.com">https://github.com/danielballoch</a>

# **Daniel Balloch**

# **SKILLS**

HTML5, CSS3, styled components, JavaScript, React.js, Gatsby.js, version control, I've also done projects in Next.js and webflow. I've used Node.js (Express/Typescript) for a few projects implementing different APIs from Xero, ActiveCampaign, Snipcart, Stripe to different CMS like Prismic, Contentful etc, and would love to learn more tools/systems to help businesses. I have some skills in prototyping, design, and editing (adobeXD, photoshop, premiere) and have worked with basic SQL and NoSQL databases (PostgreSQL & MongoDB).

Freelance projects are summarised below and also showcased online at: <a href="https://www.danielballoch.com/">https://www.danielballoch.com/</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/thoughtfulH0/">https://www.facebook.com/thoughtfulH0/</a>

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Glacier International - Toyota Tundra & Sequoia dealer.

April 2022 - PRESENT

- Web design & development for a 6 page mobile friendly website. For an example of responsive design on the website see the grid setup at the top of the careers page and how this transitions on mobile.
- "Build Your Tundra/Sequoia" pages, which let users select vehicle grade, bed, and colour options, updating vehicle image and price accordingly.
- Order page with automated Xero (accounting software) contact & invoice creation/email. Information is also sent to the Glacier ActiveCampaign account at each stage so the Digital Marketing team at VYNE can follow up with customers.
- Google Places API integrated for address suggestions on order form.
- Abandoned cart email feature as requested by VYNE Marketing Team.
- Outsourced a small section of Xero API to a friend who was looking for work experience, collaborating on Github. Also worked alongside SEO specialist Matthew from Netbloom, and the digital marketing team at VYNE in the later stages.
- Support form with automated response email via sendgrid.
- Tools: html, css, gatsby.js, react, node.js, typescript, Xero API, ActiveCampaign, Sendgrid API, Google Places API.
- Code: <a href="https://github.com/danielballoch/GlacierInternational">https://github.com/danielballoch/GlacierInternational</a>
- Live: <a href="https://glacier.nz">https://glacier.nz</a>

#### Rob Quin — Criminal & Traffic Lawyer

- Simple 2 page website redesign with contact form.
- This was a small project helping Rob refresh his web design, making it mobile responsive, and adding a contact form to streamline his workflow.
- Tools: html, css, gatsby.js, getForm API.
- Code: <a href="https://github.com/danielballoch/R0">https://github.com/danielballoch/R0</a>
- Live: <a href="https://www.robquin.co.nz/">https://www.robquin.co.nz/</a>

## Vanman Logistics - Airport Shuttle & Courier Solutions

March 2021 - January 2022

- Web design & development for 4 page mobile friendly website + CMS.
- 3 stage shuttle booking form using sendgrid API, and with Google Recaptcha integrated for spam protection.
- In person communication with clients Dave & Heather.
- Tools: html, css, gatsby.js, node.js, sendgrid API, prismic CMS.
- Code: <a href="https://github.com/danielballoch/Vanman">https://github.com/danielballoch/Vanman</a>
- Link: <a href="https://www.vanman.kiwi/">https://www.vanman.kiwi/</a>

# Raglan Landscape Supplies - Landscape Supplies & Garden Center

April 2022 - May 2022

- This was a small job for a webflow designer. His client wanted a calculator customers could use to figure out how much of a given material they needed before ordering. He designed the website, all I did was code a small calculator section and add pre-existing css styles.
- Tools: html, css, javascript, Webflow.
- Link: <a href="https://www.raglanlandscapesupplies.co.nz/sand-metal-and-drainage/scoria-7-25mm-drainage-or-decorative">https://www.raglanlandscapesupplies.co.nz/sand-metal-and-drainage/scoria-7-25mm-drainage-or-decorative</a>

#### **EDUCATION**

- · Udemy: The Complete Web Developer in 2020: Zero to Mastery
- Udemy: The Web Developer Bootcamp
- · CompTIA A+ 901
- · First Aid Trained
- · Red Shirts Customer Service Certificate
- · NCEA Level 3, Hillcrest High School, Hamilton, 2017

#### **AWARDS**

- -HHS Video Production Award 2017
- -Distinctions in Digital Technology Essentials (2013) & Programming (2014)
- -Diligence in APE (2017) & Merit endorsement in English (2015)
- -HHS Prem Basketball MVP 2017

#### Referees

Malcom King: Most recent client with Glacier International project, phone 027 288 6372.

Aaron Ross: Supervisor at Urgent couriers (Have contracted with Urgent couriers for the past 2 years as my main income), phone 027 342 5188.